ガキッ！
Episode 3
There Are Things
Even Magic Cannot Do
（夏村・心の声）
≪この力　やはり姫様の…≫
This power...
It is indeed the princess's.
（夏村）ふん！
うわっ！
（夏村）まだまだ未熟！
You're still inexperienced!
おい　葉風　あいつ強すぎるだろ！
What the hell, Hakaze?!
He's too strong!
（葉風・通信）
だから言ったであろう！
I told you that!
He is a true mage,
（葉風）
ヤツは　本物の魔法使いだ。→
使える魔具も魔法も
限られているお前とは違う。→
unlike yourself who can only use limited magic and talismans.
（通信）だいたい　町なかで
鎖部の者と戦おうというのが→
You were a fool from the start, trying to fight a Kusaribe in the city.
無謀なのだ。
うるせぇ。　どうせ　この先…。
Shut up.
From now on...
ちっ！　もう終わりか。
It's already used up.
Let's see, what should I do now?
さて　どうするかな。
腹も減ってきたし…。
Not to mention, I'm getting hungry.
おっ　助かる。　えっ？
Oh, thanks...
Wha—
吉野！
Yoshino?!
お前　バカか!?
The hell? Are you stupid?
俺につきあう義理はないって
言っただろ！
I said you didn't have to stay with me!
（滝川吉野）それがさ→
Well, you see...
I imagined my girlfriend scolding me and saying,
友達を大事にしない人は
嫌いですって→
"I don't like people who aren't good to their friends."
彼女に怒られそうでね。
Pathetic.
情けねぇな。
女の言うことなんて気にすんなよ。
Don't worry about what some chick says.
お前は　人の言うこと気にしろよ。
あっ。
Maybe you should worry a little more about what people say.
ヤツだ。
ヤツって？
It's him.
Him?
≪ガサッ
ん？
ごめん。
いいから合わせろ！
Sorry.
Whatever, just keep up!
えっ？
参る！
Huh?
Here I come.
ドォーン！
仲間…　か？
He has an ally, eh?
なっ？　うまくいっただろ。
See? I told you it'd work.
If we'd messed up, that car could've blown up.
下手したら
車ごと　バラバラだったけどね。
That's why I told you to keep up.
だから合わせろって言ったんだよ。
ちっ！
（葉風・通信）真広　ここは退け！→
Mahiro, you should retreat.
You won't gain anything by fighting Natsumura right now!
今　夏村と戦っても益はない。
黙れよ。
Shut up.
第一
あんなのから逃げる程度じゃ→
Besides, if I have to run from a guy like that,
愛花を殺した野郎を
ぶっ殺せないだろ？
I can't kill Aika's murderer.
（葉風）ええい　なぜ分からんのだ！
Why won't you understand?!
（葉風）
≪妹を殺した犯人に近づいて→
Getting closer to his sister's killer
has him more worked up than I'd expected.
思ったより気が立っていたか≫
≪だが　このままでは
真広に勝ち目はない≫
But there's no way Mahiro can win like this.
なあ　真広　ここは
葉風さんの言うこと聞いとこうよ。
Hey, Mahiro...
I think we should listen to Miss Hakaze.
Isn't she the world's most powerful mage?
史上最強の魔法使いなんだし。
自称だろ　自称。
Yeah, self-proclaimed.
That aside,
それに　僕らの使える
防御と高速移動の魔法だけで→
can we take that guy on  with only defensive and high-speed movement magic?
あの男に対抗できるのか？
They have other uses.
ほかに　こんな使い方もできるぜ。
すごいな。
医者いらずだぜ。
Amazing...
Don't even need a doctor.
じゃあ　電撃とか
ファイヤーボールとか→
Then what about using lightning, fireballs,
or summoning monsters?
モンスター召喚とかは？
ああ？
What?
This isn't a game...
ゲームじゃ…　ねぇんだぞ。
そんなの使えたら危ないだろ。
It'd be dangerous if we could do any of that.
へっ。　よし。
All right...
≪今でも
十分　危ないと思うけど…≫
I think you're dangerous enough already.
吉野。
あっ！
Yoshino!
葉風　魔法について
レクチャーしてやれ。
Hakaze, give him a lecture about magic.
３分だ。　その間に
魔法の使い方を覚えとけ。
You have three minutes.
Learn how to use magic in that time.
Don't make it sound so easy.
簡単に言うなよ。
行くぜ　魔法使い！
Here I come, mage!
ガキッ！
あっ！
（葉風・通信）吉野　状況を説明しろ。
Yoshino, tell me what's going on.
あっ　はい。
真広が　槍を持った魔法使いに→
Right...
Mahiro just barreled into the man with the spear!
突っ込んでいきました！
（葉風・通信）まったく　あいつは…。
Damn him...
大丈夫なのか？　もし相手が→
Will he be all right?
If that guy uses offensive magic...
攻撃魔法でも使ってきたら…。
（葉風・通信）安心しろ。→
You needn't worry.
The Kusaribe clan has no such thing as offensive magic.
鎖部の魔法に　いわゆる
攻撃魔法は存在しない。→
Our magic is used to protect the logic of this world,
我らの魔法は　この世の理を守り→
as well as to repair, heal, and manage it.
直し　癒やし　治めるための力。→
We don't have the ability to do direct harm or act against that logic.
直接的に
物や理を破壊する力はない。
でも…。
But...
どうした　槍男！
あの槍の威力は？
What's wrong, spear guy?
Then what's with the spear's power?
（葉風・通信）
槍の先端を防御フィールドで覆い→
The spear's tip is surrounded by a force field.
He is using agility magic to wield it at lightning speed.
高速魔法で打ち出しているのだ。→
This does lead to destruction,
結果的に
破壊に結び付いただけで→
決して　それ自体に
破壊力があるわけではない。
but it's not the magic itself that's destructive.
So it's like wearing armor and then hitting someone really hard?
鎧を着て　思いっ切り
ぶん殴るみたいな感じですか？
Something like that.
（葉風・通信）まあ　そういうことだ。
でも　葉風さん→
But, Miss Hakaze,
お互いに　鎧…
防御魔法をまとっているんですよ？
they both have armor and are using defensive magic.
永遠に勝敗は　つかないんじゃ…。
Doesn't that mean neither can prevail?
They wouldn't sustain much damage just from being hit.
（葉風・通信）ぶつかっただけでは
双方ダメージは負わん。→
However, once defensive magic is invoked,
が　防御魔法は
一度の発動で　持続する時間と→
耐えられる負荷に上限がある。→
there are limits to its duration and durability.
So if they use enough power to exceed those limits,
そして
上限を超える力がかかれば→
防御は破れてしまう。
the defense will break.
And if someone is being attacked when that happens?
その状態で攻撃を受けたら…。
If the opponent's attack uses the force field,
（葉風・通信）相手の攻撃が
防御フィールドを用いたものならば→
I doubt a human body could withstand it.
生身の肉体では
耐えられんだろうな。
真広の援護に行きます！
I'm going to help Mahiro!
（葉風・通信）
それより聞け。　鎖部の魔法とは→
More importantly, listen!
Kusaribe magic exists only by drawing power from the Tree of Genesis.
はじまりの樹の力を
借り受けることにある。
The Tree of Genesis?
はじまりの樹？
It's the god of the Kusaribe clan.
（葉風）我ら鎖部の神であり
この世の始まりにあって→
A mighty tree, which has existed since the beginning of time, that rules all reason.
あまねく理をつかさどる
大いなる樹だ。→
When we draw strength from that great power,
その偉大なる力を
借り受けることにより→
we derive the ability to protect its logic.
我らは　理を守る力を得る。→
To use this power, two things are required.
その力を得るには
二つのものが必要になる。→
一つは　音声。
鎖部の者が　声によって→
The first is a voice.
With the voice of one from the Kusaribe clan,
はじまりの樹に　力の貸与を
申し入れることにより→
we may request power from the Tree of Genesis,
and the magic is then invoked.
魔法は発動する。
でも　僕の持っている魔具は→
But the talisman I have...
頭でイメージすれば
発動しましたけど。
I used its power just by imagining it.
That's because I already verbally set rules
（葉風・通信）それは
私が　あらかじめ　音声で→
as to how this magic can be used.
どんな魔法を
どんな条件で発動するか→
申し入れてあるからだ。
これも高等技術だがな。
That is a high-level technique.
で　もう一つ必要なのは？
And what's the other thing you need?
（葉風）貸与する力に応じ→
In return for the power it lends us,
we must make an offering to the Tree of Genesis.
はじまりの樹に
供物を捧げねばならん。→
What the Tree of Genesis wants
はじまりの樹が欲するのは
文明の産物。→
are the fruits of civilization.
Things created by man's knowledge,
人の知識によって造られた
道具　機械　構造物…→
like tools, machines, and structures.
It must make direct contact with one of those items.
それらに直接　触れねばならん。→
Once the offering is acknowledged,
そして　捧げられた供物は
その証しに塵となる。
the item will turn to dust.
ガキッ！
バリン！
先ほどより動きがいいな。
You seem to be moving better than before.
仲間が現れたせいか？
Is it because your friend showed up?
You must be joking...
冗談言うな。　少しだけ
本気出すことにしたんだ→
I just decided to take this a little more seriously.
Just a bit...
少～しだけな！
Tree within the tree,
樹の中の樹　大樹の中の大樹→
great tree within the great tree,
tree that has existed since the beginning, Tree of Genesis.
始まりにありし　はじまりの樹→
Hear my words, and grant my wish.
我が言葉において聞き届けよ。
ドカーン！
（葉風・通信）
そして　より高度な技術→
Also, the more advanced the technique,
より進んだ知識によって
造られたものほど強い力を得る。→
and the more advanced the knowledge used to create the offering,
the more power we receive.
孤島に流された私が
ろくに魔法を使えないのも→
The reason I can barely use magic now is because I'm trapped on a desert island,
必要な供物がないからだ。
without the necessary items.
Well, a desert island is a far cry from civilization.
無人島なんて
文明から程遠いですもんね。
≪けど　なんか変な感じだ≫
But something's strange.
A magic that requires civilization?
≪文明が必要な魔法なんて…≫
Not to mention
≪それに
金属と化した生物たち…≫
the living things that have metallicized...
≪これに　なんの意味がある？≫
What does it all mean?
静かになったか。
You've finally quieted down.
はあっ！
ゴツ！
ようやく分かったぜ。
I get it now...
防御魔法さえ張ってりゃ…。
As long as I have a defensive spell on,
I can inflict damage without a weapon!
生身でも
ダメージを与えられるってな！
はあっ！　どうした　どうした！
Come on! What's the matter?!
≪自らもダメージを負うのが
怖くないのか？　この少年≫
Doesn't this boy fear the damage he'll inflict on himself?
はあっ！
ドカッ！
ふっ！
ふん！
Is that all you have?
それで終わりか？
こいつ…。
Damn it.
（葉風・通信）夏村の
魔法使いとしてのレベルは→
Natsumura's level as a mage isn't that high.
高くない。　だが　戦闘に関しては→
But when it comes to fighting,
he's the finest in the clan.
一族で　最も磨かれている。→
And also...
しかも　そこには…。
そうか　供物は　どこにでもある。
That's right... There are offerings everywhere.
You catch on pretty fast.
（葉風・通信）飲み込みがいいな。
魔具頼みの貴様らと違い→
Unlike you two, who must rely on talismans,
Natsumura can use all the magic he wishes.
夏村は
いくらでも魔法を使えるのだ。
≪ドォーン
真広！
Mahiro!
真広！　真広！
Mahiro! Mahiro!
どこ行ったんだよ…。
Where'd he go?
がはっ！
野郎…。
Bastard...
Will the talismans expire first,
（夏村）魔具が尽きるのが先か→
or will it be your luck?
貴様の命運が尽きるのが先か→
I wonder which.
どっちかな？
あの槍男…。
Damn that spear guy!
（愛花の声）だらしないですね。
はっ！
How careless.
（回想）
((ただの風邪じゃねぇぞ　これ))
This isn't an ordinary cold.
((頭痛ぇ))
My head hurts.
（愛花）((だから　こうやって
看病してあげてるじゃないですか))
Which is why I'm here, taking care of you.
((ああ～　俺　もう死ぬかも))
Man, I could die any minute.
I want some canned peaches...
((桃缶　食いてぇなぁ))
((それくらいじゃ
死にはしませんよ))
You won't die that easily.
Yeah, you're right.
ああ　そうだな。
これくらいで
死んでる場合じゃねぇよな…。
I can't die this easily...
（葉風・通信）早く真広を退かせろ！
Hurry and get Mahiro to fall back!
ダメだ　出やしない！　あっ！
It's no use! He isn't picking up.
（山本）爆撃で　町を封鎖!?
You're going to use bombs to quarantine the area?
[TEL]（早河）今回の黒鉄病は
被害が大きすぎる。→
There have been too many casualties from the black iron syndrome.
ヘリからの長距離攻撃で
町をつなぐトンネル　鉄橋を→
We've been ordered to bomb tunnels and railroads to the city,
using helicopters at long range.
破壊するよう指示が出された。
（山本）でも　乱暴すぎない？
Isn't that a bit excessive?
[TEL]（早河）考えてもみろ。
見るかぎりの生物が→
Think about it.
Who would want to go to a region
金属化している異常な地域に
誰が入りたがる？→
where most of its inhabitants have metallicized?
そのうえ　原因が　まるで不明。→
On top of that, there's no known cause,
防護服を着込んだとしても
安心はできない。
and protective gear won't guarantee safety.
Wait, then what about me?
（山本）いや…　じゃあ　私は？
[TEL]（早河）追って次の連絡をする。
We will contact you again at a later time.
[TEL]　ツーツー（不通音）
ちょっと！
Wait!
もう…。
Jeez...
ピーッ！
カチッ
ドカン！
They're trying to quarantine the city?
町を封鎖するつもりか？
（葉風・通信）何かあったのか？
あっ　いえ…。
Did something happen?
Oh, it's nothing.
それより
葉風さん　一つ聞いていいですか？
More importantly, Miss Hakaze,
may I ask you something?
（葉風）なんだ？
（通信）鎖部の魔法で→
What is it?
Is there any way to resurrect the dead using Kusaribe magic?
死者を生き返らせたりは
できないんですか？
言ったはずだ　鎖部の魔法は→
I already told you.
Our magic is used to protect the logic of this world,
この世の理を守り　直し　癒やし
治めるための力だと。→
as well as to fix, heal, and manage it.
（通信）すでに死んだ者を
墓の下から呼び戻すのが→
Do you think that bringing the dead back from the grave
世の理に
かなうことだと思うのか？
would be within this world's logic?
No.
いえ…。
真広が犯人を見つけて
殺すとばかり言うんで→
Mahiro keeps talking about finding the murderer and killing them,
なぜかと思っていただけです。
so I wondered why.
≫ドカン
あっ。
魔法なんてものがあれば→
If magic is available in the world,
that should be the first thing to wish for.
最初に願うのは
それのはずなのに…。
However,
だがな　真広は　最初から
妹を生き返らせてくれとは→
from the start,
Mahiro never asked for his sister to be resurrected.
願わなかったぞ。
（通信）えっ？
Huh?
（葉風）ヤツは　傲慢で
自己中心的で　いけ好かんが→
He is arrogant, self-centered, and not very likeable,
ヤツなりに
理解しているのであろう→
but he seems to comprehend this much well enough.
There are no convenient miracles,
己に都合のいい奇跡など
決して起こらんことを。
そして
犯してはならん理があることを。
and there is logic that should be inviolable.
You're right.
そうですね。
奇跡なんて不合理ですから。
Miracles are irrational by nature.
（通信）じゃあ　真広を捜します。
Well, I'm going to keep looking for Mahiro.
What was that?
≪なんだ？
まるで　愛花という妹に→
It almost sounded like he wanted this Aika to return to life...
生き返ってほしいようだったが…。→
分からんな。　滝川吉野→
I don't understand you, Takigawa Yoshino.
何を内に抱えている？≫
What are you hiding?
Hey!
よう！
これで追い詰めたつもりか!?
You think you've cornered me so easily?!
くらえ！
バキュン！
Take this!
無駄なことを。
バキュン！
How futile.
バキュン！　バキュン！
くたばれ！
バキュン！
Die!
ドカーン！
うわっ！
真広…　あっ。
Mahiro...
Takigawa                    Yoshino
葉風さん　鎖部の魔法は→
Miss Hakaze,
Takigawa                    Yoshino
Kusaribe magic is used to protect the world's logic,
この世の理を守り
癒やし　治めるための力って→
and to heal and manage it, right?
言いましたよね。
（葉風・通信）そうだが…。
Correct.
だったら…。
Then...
へへっ…　ざまぁみろ。　はっ！
Serves you right.
This is the end.
（夏村）
ここまでだ。　悪いようにはしない。
I will not take this any further.
You have no duty or reason to lose your life.
命まで賭ける義理や理由は
なかろう。
I don't have a duty.
義理はねぇが　理由ならあるさ→
But I do have a reason...
十分にな。
Plenty of reasons!
これは…　ん!?
This is...
くっ！
ガキン！
Yoshino?
吉野！
いいから　こっちだ！
Come on, this way!
治癒魔法で
俺の居場所を突き止めたのか。
You found me by using healing magic?
It was difficult,
苦労したよ。
でも　ちょうどいい。　もうすぐだ。
but nice timing.
Almost time...
真広　トンネルを抜けたら
僕に合わせて→
Mahiro, once we exit the tunnel,
keep up with me, and head for the forest!
森の中に飛び込め！
えっ？
What?
どこへ逃げても同じだ。
It doesn't matter where you go. Nothing will change.
合わせろ！
（夏村）ふん！
Follow me!
ドカン！
ドカーン！
Perfect timing...
ぴったりだったな。
今の　なんだよ。
What the hell was that?
攻撃ヘリのミサイル。
はあ？
A missile from a helicopter.
What?
町を封鎖しようと　北側の鉄橋から
攻撃してたからさ→
I saw them blow up the northern bridge to quarantine the area.
順番からいって
このトンネルが最後かと思って。
Taking it in order,
I thought this tunnel would be last.
お前な…　最初から説明しとけ。
You know...
You should've explained that at the start.
でも　うまくいっただろ？
But it went well, didn't it?
You fools...
まったく　バカどもめ。
しかし　滝川吉野…
とっさに治癒魔法で→
However, Takigawa Yoshino.
In an instant, you managed to think of finding Mahiro with healing magic,
真広の居場所を
突き止めることを思いつき→
as well as to predict when the helicopters would attack.
更に　ヘリからの攻撃の
タイミングまで予測するとは→
なかなか興味深い男だ。
You're a very interesting man.
してやられたか…。
It seems I was defeated.
（夏村・通信）
左門殿　申し訳ありません。→
My apologies, Mr. Samon.
逃がしました。
（左門）かまわん。
They have escaped.
It doesn't matter.
姫様が　あくまで
我らの邪魔をするというなら→
If the princess is going to get in our way,
再び　まみえるはずだ。
we will run into them again.
それに
どういう事情で　その二人が→
Furthermore,
I still don't know how those two got involved with the princess.
姫様とつながったかは知らんが→
This is a battle that will decide the world's fate.
この世の命運を左右する戦い…→
If they were merely been brought into this by chance,
ただ巻き込まれただけの者に
戦いきれはせん。
they will not last for long.
（夏村・通信）なら　いいのですが。
I hope that is the case, then.
So the logic created by the Tree of Genesis
（左門）
はじまりの樹が造りし世の理は→
やはり　姫様に味方するのか…。
will indeed side with the princess, after all...
One year goes by.
（子供たち）♪♪　ひとつとせ
（子供たち）
♪♪　くさりのおさとは　やまのなか
The valley of chains lies deep in the mountains.
（子供たち）
♪♪　きつねも　おにも　ちかづけぬ
Foxes and ogres cannot approach.
（お爺さん）若衆が
あくまで成し遂げる気だなぁ。
So the young ones seem hell-bent on trying to accomplish it...
The Tree of Genesis is late returning.
It seems that way.
（お婆さん）そうですねぇ。
They went off to the mountains.
（お爺さん）
みんな　お山に行きよって。
The rivers, fields, and mountains will all turn to iron.
（お婆さん）そうですねぇ。
（お爺さん）だが　姫様相手に→
It seems that way...
However, I doubt things will be so easy
Will all turn to iron...
そうたやすく
事が運ぶとも思えんがなぁ。
if their opponent is the princess.
Two years go by.
（お婆さん）ほんに　ほんに。
（子供たち）♪♪　くさりのおさとに
Indeed, indeed.
When the sun sets in the valley of chains...
（子供たち）♪♪　ひがしずみゃ
（葉風）
♪♪　おとしたくびも　かまにくべ
Burn the heads that have fallen in the oven...
（葉風）
♪♪　はじまりのきさま　おいしげる
The Tree of Genesis will thrive.
[ｶﾁﾝｺ]（アナウンサー）トンネル崩落事故による
死傷者なし。→
There have been no casualties from the tunnel's collapse.
局地的な地滑りによるものか→
It's currently under investigation whether a local mudslide was the cause.
現在　国防軍の災害派遣部隊が
現地入りし…。
The Self-Defense Force's disaster response team
死傷者なし…　か。
has entered the area to investigate.
No casualties, huh?
しかし　もったいなかったな。
Still, what a waste.
あれ　とどめ刺せただろ。
We could've finished him.
魔法使いを倒すのが
いちばんの目的じゃないだろ。
Our top priority isn't defeating a mage.
Yoshino is right.
（葉風・通信）吉野の方が正しい。→
We can stop the revival of the Tree of Exodus
左門たちと
正面から　ぶつからずとも→
絶園の樹の復活は
妨害できるのだ。
without directly confronting Samon and his followers.
いいや　魔法使いは　直接
倒さなきゃならないだろ。
Wrong.
We should fight the mages head-on.
どういうことだ？
お前と別れたあと→
What are you talking about?
After you left,
葉風の魔法で　愛花を殺した野郎が
かなり絞れた。
we managed to use Hakaze's magic to shorten the list of suspects.
犯人は　鎖部一族の誰かだ。
The killer is
someone from the Kusaribe clan.
まさか…。
（葉風・通信）間違いない。→
It can't be.
There's no doubt about it.
当時　一族を治めていた身として
申し訳が立たんが→
I can't apologize enough, especially as I was clan head at the time.
犯人は　一族の者だ。
But the killer is from the clan.
What is this connection?
≪なんだ　このつながりは…≫
≪こんな偶然　あるのか？≫
Do coincidences like this happen?
Or was this somehow inevitable?
≪それとも　これは何かの必然？≫
Don't worry about it.
気にするな　これも　何かの因果さ。
This, too, is just another kind of fate.
何かって　なんだよ。
A kind of fate?
What are you talking about?
kimi to miteta nagareboshi oikakete
Chasing the shooting star that we saw together
Reaching this place all alone
hitori bocchi konna toko made kiteta
Hiding the feelings I wanted to express to you
kinou kimi ni ienakatta kimochi o
kotoba no naka kakusu no
within words
tooku hanarete itemo douka todokimasu you ni
No matter how far we are separated,
please let it reach you
kono michi no saki ni matsu unmei nante
The fate waiting for us down this road
is not yet known
ima wa mada
dare mo mada
shiranai kedo
by anyone
To the future drawn by numbed fingers
kajikan da yubisaki de egaita mirai he
With you we can make it
kimi to nara ikerutte
nee sonna ki ga shiteta nda
That's what I feel
kitto
with certainty
I wonder what would have happened if you hadn't met Yoshino.
（葉風）もし
貴様と吉野が出会わなかったら→
We weren't friends.
どうなっていただろうな。
友達じゃなかったんですよ。
If I hadn't met Yoshino...
吉野と出会わなかったら…。
Yes, we avoided each other.
There's something about him that I'll never understand.
ええ　避けてましたよ。
あいつは
よく分からねぇとこがあるからな。
I didn't want  to deal with him anymore.
僕は　もう　あいつには
関わる気がなかったんですが…。
I see.
This story is vaguely unpleasant.
（葉風）なるほど　微妙に嫌な話だ。
Episode 4
The
Cursed Pair